# Chris Villanueva

Extremely organized with years of experience in successful planning and execution of small to large projects. Proven ability to balance priorities, meet deadlines, and produce top quality work. Focuses on adaptability and taking initiative in ensuring good teamwork.

**EXPERIENCE** 

### **Metadata Coordinator**

Spafax Dec 2019 - Apr 2020

- Developed Excel VBA tools to improve workflow and quality of spreadsheets.
- Analyzed data on inflight entertainment systems and online databases.
- Coordinated with different media distributors to gather media assets and ensure copyright information is updated.

# **Aerial Telecommunication Analyst**

Ridgeline Telecom May 2019 - Nov 2019

- Created new methods and programs to automate data entry work which increased Excel spreadsheet productivity.
- Evaluated telecommunication network problems and constructed efficient solutions.
- Checked the quality of other colleagues' work to ensure accuracy and provided constructive feedback.

## **Head Server and Caterer**

Stonefire Grill Feb 2012 - Jan 2019

- Resolved customer problems by investigating issues and answering questions.
- Ensured a clean, comfortable, and inviting environment.
- Successfully worked under fast paced and high pressure situations.
- Trained and led teams up to twelve people to cater up to 1500 guests.

#### Vice President

Association for Computing Machinery-Women (CSUF Chapter) Aug 2017 - May 2018

- Assisted club activities that help promote women and other underrepresented groups in technology.
- Designed educational programs to encourage students to take a career path in the science and engineering fields.
- Recruited new members by advertising and engaging with students.
- Handled media productions to help promote and provide insight of organization.

#### **Lead Coordinator**

California State University of Fullerton Computer Science Department Key Events:

ACM-W Code Camp
STEM Expo 2017
Creative Coding
ECS Diversity & Leadership Summit
Feb 2017 - May 2017
July 2017 - Oct 2017
Jan 2018 - May 2018
Jan 2018 - April 2018

- Maintained effective communication between different teams simultaneously.
- Implemented new systematic structures to improve workflow and efficiency.
- Prepared various reports of financial status with visual representation.
- Analyzed budget and tracked purchases.
- Resolved conflicts while still delivering the desired outcome within the deadline.
- Reached out to professionals to come and provide insight about the technology industry to students.

5 Springfield Irvine, CA 92604 (949) 701 - 6819 chrisvillanpro@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/chrisvillan www.chrisvillanpro.com

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor's in Computer Science**

California State University, Fullerton

Aug 2016 - May 2018

## Associate's in Computer Languages

Irvine Valley College Sep 2012 - May 2016

#### **SKILLS**

**Project Management** 

**Problem Solver** 

Critical Thinking

**Efficient** 

Advanced MS Excel

**Pivot Tables** 

Software Tool Development

Visual Models

**Decision Making** 

Resourceful

Cost Effective

Media Production

# **Technical (IT) Skills**

#### **Software Tools**

MS Word, MS Excel, MS Powerpoint, MS Visual Studio, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Premiere

## **Operating Systems**

Windows 10, Mac, Linux

#### Languages

Python, Visual Basic, SQL, C++, HTML, CSS